(ﾘﾄﾞ)申し訳ありません｡➡
I beg your pardon, my lady.
エルが脱走しました！
But El has escaped!
(ﾌｧﾊﾞﾛ･ﾚｵｰﾈ)カイザル！
Kaisar!
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)ぬぅ～！
キン！
ボォーン‼
(ﾆｰﾅ･ﾄﾞﾗﾝｺﾞ)
ありがと ムガロちゃん｡
Thank you, Mugaro!
ちょっと
変わったかもしれないけど➡
You may have changed a little bit,
でも
ムガロちゃんはムガロちゃんだ｡
but you're still Mugaro!
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)乗れ！
Get in!
Azazel.
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)
アザゼル お前の力を貸してくれ｡
Please help us.
悪魔を助けたいのだろう？
You want to save the demons, don't you?
協力してくれ｡
Help us.
(隊長)
闘技場から脱走した者たちは➡
The fugitives from the arena
are still at large.
今も逃走中です｡➡
王都の外に逃げ出せぬよう
厳重に包囲網を張っております｡
We've set a perimeter around the capital
to ensure they do not escape the city.
The man who helped them escape
(ｼｬﾘｵｽ17世)
逃走に手を貸したという男➡
ファバロ･レオーネに違いない｡
(隊長)おそらくは｡➡
was assuredly Favaro Leone.
Yes.
We will handle him with the others.
まとめて処理いたします｡➡
And also regarding the red dragon,
we will be sure to slay it next time.
赤い竜に関しても
次こそは必ず始末します｡
ヤツらのいる所に
赤い竜は幾度となく現れました｡➡
The red dragon has appeared
many times wherever that bunch
is involved.
We will surely happen upon the dragon
if we pursue them.
追えば いずれ出会えましょう｡
Kill it on sight.
見つけしだい殺せ｡
Is there something I should know
about the red dragon?
赤い竜に何か？
何もない｡ 行け｡
No.
Go.
Why did you let them escape?
(ｶﾞﾌﾞﾘｴﾙ)なぜ 逃がしたのです！
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)申し訳ございません｡
My apologies.
How could you let this happen?
(ｶﾞﾌﾞﾘｴﾙ)あなたがいながら
なんたる失態！➡
I know that you must understand what it
means for us to lose El at this time.
今 エルを失うことの意味が
分からないわけではないでしょう｡
We will send a search party immediately.
すぐに捜索いたします｡
(ｶﾞﾌﾞﾘｴﾙ)当然です｡➡
Obviously. We must get El back.
必ず エルを取り戻すのです｡
I will go.
≫(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)私が行きます｡
(２人)あっ｡
Stand down!
(ﾘﾄﾞ)控えなさい！
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)あの子が 人に捕まれば➡
He will be killed if he's ever captured
by the humans.
殺されます｡
黙って見過ごすなどできません｡
I cannot stand by and watch.
You would only get in the way.
あなたが行っても
足手まといになるだけです｡
Please forgive my insolence,
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)お言葉ながら
エルに信用されていない➡
but leaving this matter to those
who are not trusted by El
あなた方に任せて
なんとかなるとは思えません｡
is not very reassuring.
I will go alone if I have to.
一人でも 私は行きます｡
Wait, Jeanne!
(ｶﾞﾌﾞﾘｴﾙ)待ちなさい ジャンヌ！
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)私にお任せを｡
Please leave this to me.
カラン カラン…
(ﾊﾝｻ)ひどいことしますねぇ｡
This is awful.
リタ 大丈夫かな？
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)分からねぇ｡
Do you think Rita is okay?
I don't know.
≪(ﾘﾀ)あんたたち まさか それ➡
Is that your idea of a disguise?
変装してるつもり？
リタだ！
(ﾘﾀ)そうよ｡
It's Rita!
In the flesh.
Rage of Bahamut
They are the same
and lose themselves
Cuz there are lots of roads to go
And the path suddenly seems rougher
I wanna walk straight ahead
Knock down another dream
Most broke before they ever came true
But walk this way
Get out of my way
Depends on the way you think it
To a yielding heart
the future, hope,
despair and worry all look all the same
So much that you'll turn down the truth
that lied to you that day
when you were prepared for it all.
You go your way, don't you?
But walk this way
Get out of my way
うん｡
≪(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)アザゼルは どこ行った？
Where did Azazel go?
知らねぇ｡ 朝から見てねぇな｡
No idea. Haven't seen him since morning.
ほら｡
Here.
どうした？
What's wrong?
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)今度は
爆発しないだろうな？
This one won't explode, will it?
さあな｡
さあなって お前！
Who knows?
What do you mean, who knows?
≫師匠！
ん？
Master!
(ﾘﾀ)ただいま｡
生きてたんですね 師匠！
We're home.
You're alive, Master!
さすが 師匠は無敵です｡
おう｡
You're invincible!
Yeah, and I can't believe the luck
you seem to have.
おめぇも
悪運だけは強ぇみてぇだな｡
あっ？ なんだ？ その顔｡
What's that look for?
ううっ…｡
ちょっ… お前➡
How are you okay with me,
but you blush with Kaisar?
俺は大丈夫なのに なんで
カイザルに 顔赤くしてんだよ？
(ﾊﾝｻ)なんだクワァ
この感じ 久しぶりですね｡
This is bringing back some memories.
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)ああ～ 酒が飲みてぇ｡
I want some wine.
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)その少年は？
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)ん？➡
Who is that boy?
ジャンヌの息子だ｡
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)ジャンヌ様は？
That's Jeanne's son.
Where is Jeanne?
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)まだ 神の国だ｡
Still in the land of the gods.
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)私はカイザル･リドフｧルド｡
君のお母さんの元部下だ｡
I am Kaisar Lidfard.
I used to serve your mother.
Someone's gotten angsty
while they were gone.
少し見ないうちに
生意気になったわね｡
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)私たちは➡
We want to determine
what King Charioce is trying to do.
シャリオス王が このあと
何をしようとしているのか➡
それを見極めたいと考えている｡➡
先の戦いで 王が使用した兵器➡
The weapon the king used
in the last battle,
あの破壊力は危険すぎる｡
its power is far too dangerous.
王の意思しだいでは
１０年前と変わらぬ危機が➡
If the king so wishes,
the world could be put in the same danger
it was in ten years ago.
世界に訪れるかもしれない｡
(ｴﾙ)あれさえなければ
人を正しい道に戻すことができる｡
If it wasn't for that weapon, humanity
could be guided back to the right path.
(ｴﾙ)僕の力ならできる！
I can do it with my power.
What are you talking about, brat?
何言ってんだ？ このガキ｡
確かに あの兵器を封印できれば➡
That's true. If that weapon can be stripped of its power,
王の真意がどうであれ
破壊は防げるだろう｡
we could prevent destruction
no matter what the king's intentions are.
しかし どうやって？
腕輪よ｡
But how?
The bracelet.
えっ 腕輪？
私 見た➡
Bracelet?
I saw the king control the black thing.
王様が
あの黒いやつを動かすところを｡➡
It was reacting to his bracelet.
あの腕輪に あれは反応してた｡
その腕輪を奪う！
We will steal this bracelet!
Mugaro, if you break your promise to me...
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)
ムガロ 俺との約束を破ったら…｡
I know.
(ｴﾙ)分かってるよ…｡
Anyway, we should gather intel for now.
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)
とにかく 今は情報を集めよう｡➡
シャリオス王による強大な危機が
近づいているのなら➡
If King Charioce is putting the world
in danger,
我々で それを防ごう｡
then we must stop him.
皆 力を貸してくれ｡
We need all of your help.
I am sorry I allowed this to happen.
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)私が付いていながら
すまなかった｡
Both for letting them escape,
逃がしたこともだが 無責任に
エルの力を解放したこともだ｡
and also for the part I played
in releasing El's power irresponsibly.
はっ…｡ 我々は性急だった｡
We were rash.
エルの力に目がくらみ
その力を使いこなすための➡
We were blinded by El's powers,
and we neglected the spiritual growth
he needed to use it responsibly.
心の成長を
おろそかにしてしまった｡➡
But please believe me.
だが 信じてくれ｡
恩人であるエルを➡
I do not want to lose El.
I owe him my life.
私も失いたくない｡
下界から すぐにでも連れ戻し➡
I wish to bring him back from
the surface world,
そなたのもとで
生活させたいと願っている｡
so the two of you can be together again.
So please leave his search to me.
だから 捜索は私に任せてくれ｡
Very well.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)分かりました｡
あっ…｡
バカ者！
You fool!
I had faith that you would not let me die.
あなたなら
助けてくれると信じていました｡
このまま一緒に下界へ降りて
エルを捜してください｡
Please come with me to the surface
and help me find El.
I cannot do that.
それは無理だ｡ あっ！
あなたの命を
私たち親子は助けました｡➡
My son and I saved your life.
今度は あなたが
私たち親子のために➡
Now it is your turn to help us.
力を貸してください｡
ソフィエル様 お願いします｡
Lady Sofiel, I beseech you.
下界で そなたは追われる身だ｡
You are a fugitive in the surface world.
Can you vow to me that you will not do
anything that would attract danger?
危険な行動を勝手にせぬこと➡
それを誓えるか？
誓います｡
I vow it.
はぁ… これでは
私も バッカスと変わらんな｡
I suppose this means I am no different
from Bacchus.
I guess that does it.
ああ～
よし こんなもんかな？
わあ～！
ほんとの悪魔みたい！
I look like a real demon!
All right, I'm off to gather some intel, then!
じゃあ 情報収集に行ってくる！
あっ ちょっと！ 待ちなさい！
ふふふっ｡
Hey! Wait!
I just saw Nina skipping out of here.
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)ニーナ嬢が
元気に飛び出していったが…｡
She basically went out to play.
(ﾘﾀ)遊びに行っちゃったわ｡
あいつは気楽でいいな｡
I wish I could be so carefree.
(ﾘﾀ)あんた
ちょっと ついていきなさいよ｡
Why don't you go after her?
はあ？ なんで俺が｡
(ﾘﾀ)師匠なんでしょ？
What? Why me?
You're her master, aren't you?
関係ねぇだろ｡
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)行ってこい ボンバーヘｯド｡
What's that gotta do with it?
Just go, Bomber Head.
(ﾊﾝｻ)お嬢さんは
何に巻き込まれるクワァ➡
We don't know what she might
get herself into.
分クワァりませんクワァらね｡
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)任せたぞ ファバロ｡
We're counting on you, Favaro.
ええ～！ なんで？
Are you serious?
ああっ…｡
ドサッ
What are you doing?
何をしている？
えっ？ いや あの… う～ん…｡
私は悪魔だ！
I'm a demon!
What business does a demon have here?
悪魔が なんの用だ？
え… え～っと➡
そ… その墓は 誰の墓だ？
Whose grave is that?
It is my mother's grave.
私の母の墓だ｡
えっ！
Why are you so surprised?
なぜ驚く？
お… 驚いていない！
I'm not surprised!
She was a commoner who became
the king's concubine.
平民でありながら 王の妾となり➡
A poor woman who was discarded
as soon as she was with child.
私をはらんだ途端に捨てられた
ただの哀れな女だ｡
私に流れる王の血筋だけが
この女の生きる希望だった｡
Only the royal blood
flowing through my veins
gave her hope in her life.
She dreamed even in poverty that one day
she would be invited to the palace.
貧しい生活のなかでも いつか
王室に迎えられる日が来ると➡
夢見ていたが…｡
それが かなうことはなく➡
But she was killed by Bahamut's fire
before that day could come.
バハムートの火で
あっけなく死んでしまった｡
My father was killed
by Bahamut's fireballs as well.
私のお父さんも
バハムートの火の玉に… あっ｡
だが 皮肉なことに➡
But ironically,
it was because of Bahamut
that I was welcomed to the palace,
そのバハムートの一件により
私は王室に迎えられ➡
母に授けられた
クリスという名から➡
and I was given the new name of
Charioce XVII to replace Chris,
シャリオス１７世へと変わった｡
the one my mother had given me.
You are a demon who lives in the slums,
are you not?
お前
スラムに住む悪魔なのだろう？
えっ？ あっ… はい｡
Yes.
スラムには
一度 行ってみたかった｡
I always wanted to visit the slums.
This is perfect. Could you take me there?
ちょうどいい
案内してくれないか？
Take you? Okay.
案内？ はい…｡
He definitely knows it's me, right?
(心の声)
≪絶対にバレてるよね？≫
He said I was a demon just now, but...
≪さっきは
悪魔って言ったけど…≫
That is an interesting carving.
面白い彫刻だな｡ これをもらうよ｡
I will take this.
えっ 大丈夫？
かまわん｡
Are you sure?
It is fine.
でも 顔がバレちゃうんじゃ…｡
But won't you be recognized?
All right, let's move on.
よし 次へ行こう｡
あっ… はい｡
Okay.
(子供)行ったぞ！ 戻れ 戻れ！➡
Get back!
ほら 頑張れ 頑張れ！
Come on, get back on defense!
What are they doing there?
あれは 何をしている？
えっ？ 分かんない｡
I don't know. I think they're playing.
遊んでるんじゃない？
遊びか｡
I see.
What?
はい？
(子供たち)ああっ！
あっ 痛てっ！
(子供たち)あっ！➡
-That was awesome!
-Can you show me how to do that?
やった～！
(子供)一緒にやろうよ！
All right, here I go!
Yeah! Go!
お前も来い！
えっ!?
Come join us!
(子供)おねえちゃんも やろうよ！
(子供)早く 早く！
-Come on, miss!
-Play with us!
(子供)早く！
じゃあ 私も｡ いくぞ～！
All right, here I come!
って… ぐえっ！ ひゃあ～！
パリン
あっ！
(子供)えっ 何？ 何？
What's going on?
ほら｡
Here.
(一同)わあ～！
Let's go!
(子供)行ったぞ！
(子供)またやろうぜ！
Come on, pass it to me!
All right, go!
(子供)よっしゃ いけ！
頭のまで取っていいの？
You sure it's okay to take off
your turban too?
What does that matter to you?
何か
都合の悪いことでもあるのか？
ねえ 私 あなたに
聞きたいことが いっぱいある…｡
There are so many things
I want to ask you.
左上の壁穴を見ろ｡
Look up and to the left.
(子供)よし！ くそっ もう一回！
(子供)おい 何やってんだよ！
All right!
One more time!
Over there too.
あっちもだ｡
Let me see it already!
(子供)貸してよ～｡
(子供)いけ いけ！
あなたを監視してるの？
Are they watching you?
So close!
Let's lose them.
まくぞ｡
Do you think we lost them?
なんとか まけたか｡
たぶんね｡
I think so.
It was reacting to his bracelet.
((あの腕輪に あれは反応してた))
There's something I want to ask you.
私 あなたに聞きたいことがある｡
なんだ？
What is it?
あなたは王様で 悪魔にも神にも
嫌われることを いっぱいしている｡
You're the king,
and you've done a lot of things to make
the demons and the gods hate you.
But when you're Chris,
you're so nice to me.
なのに クリスのときは
私に優しくしたり 踊ったり➡
You dance with me and you smile at me.
悪魔の子供たちにも
笑顔を向ける｡
I don't know which one is the real you.
私には どちらの顔が
あなたの本心なのか分からない｡
I want to know what's really inside you.
私は知りたい
あなたの本当の心を！
何をもってしても➡
There is something I must achieve
at all costs.
達成しなければ
ならないことがある｡
But I cannot tell you what that is yet.
それが なんなのか
今は答えられない｡
だが 全ては
そのためだけに必要なことを➡
I can say that everything I've done as king
was necessary for that purpose.
王として選択してきた｡
その結果が 今のありさまだ｡
And this is the result.
罪悪感などというものは
とうに捨てている｡
I have long since abandoned
any feelings of guilt.
己の覚悟を己に問うためだけに➡
I only answer to my own convictions,
哀れな母の墓へと参っている｡
as I visit the grave of my poor mother.
Not once had my convictions wavered.
これまで一度たりとも
その覚悟が揺らぐことはなかった｡
ただ お前のことだけは
割り切ることができなかった｡
Not until you came into my life.
If I never met you,
お前さえ現れなければ➡
これまでどおり
王として生きていけた！
I could have lived my life as king
without a second thought.
それなのに…｡
But instead...
If only I had never met you!
お前とさえ出会わなければ！
Why you want to become a scary king,
あなたが なんで
怖い王様になろうとするのか➡
それは分からない｡
that I don't know.
けど 私は あなたのことを…｡
But, how I feel about you...
あなたが抱えているものを
一緒に背負いたい｡
I want to help you with whatever
you're dealing with.
What is it?
どうした？
バシャーン！
グオォーー！
ぷはっ！
I learned how to transform
whenever I want!
自由に
変身できるようになっちゃった！
Maybe it's because we kissed.
キスしたからかなぁ？ ふふふっ｡
グオォーー！
When can I see you next?
次は いつ会える？
分からない｡
I don't know.
やだ！
今度だ｡
No.
-Next time.
-When is next time?
今度って いつ？
いつ？ いつ？
When? When?
今度は今度だ｡
はい…｡
Next time is next time.
Okay.
But the next time we meet,
だが 次 お前と会えたなら➡
必ず
私のなすべきことを伝えよう｡
I will tell you
what I am trying to accomplish.
あっ 絶対だよ！
-Promise?
-Yes.
わあ…｡
今度は 私から会いに行く｡
Next time, I'll go to see you.
もう行け｡
うん｡
You should go.
As horrible as you are
I can't help but love you
Even while I waited
That is all I felt
Ephemeral lovers, both flawed and missing pieces
We have finally become one
in this miniature garden at the edge of sorrow
Can you hear my heart speaking?
Ah, I may no longer feel
that I want to go back in time
But there are feelings, feelings, feelings
I can only feel now
I want to run away with you, dancing
just like in a fairy tale
Don't tell me it will only be this once, darling
I am on the same ark
Sha-ra-ran-la, Sha-ra-ran-la
Yeah
Cinderella step
Sha-ra-ran-la, Sha-ra-ran-la
Yeah
Cinderella step
I knew the red dragon had him
under its spell.
やはり
赤い竜に惑わされていたか｡
This is Anatae's Kaisar!
Heaven's Jeanne!
How is it over there!
Yes!
Heaven's Jeanne here!
It's very sparkly!
It's so bright!
Next time on Rage of Bahamut:
Virgin Soul, "Invictus."
Jeanne, could you be more specific?
I told you, it's bright!
BAHA SOUL!!
Baha Baha Baha Soul
Next time too, okay?